# Aliaksandr Rasolka

Senior Backend Developer | Test Automation Lead







Email: rosolko@gmail.com

### About Me



Hi, my name's Alex and I'm a senior backend developer. As well as developing I also have experience in test automation of api, web and mobile applications. I have worked at two companies gaining teamwork and leadership skills.

I am most skilled in: Node.JS and Java.

Download this CV as PDF

## Projects

### selenide

github.com/selenide/selenide



Selenide is a framework for writing easy-to-read and easy-to-maintain automated tests in Java. It defines concise fluent API, natural language assertions and does some magic for ajax-based applications to let you focus entirely on the business logic of your tests.

Proud that I could join the team, and team accepts me. Now I can contribute to the cool library.

### wdm4j

github.com/rosolko/wdm4j



This small library aimed to automate the Selenium WebDriver binaries management inside a Java project.

Another small library I wrote as a way if learning Java.

### WebDriverManager.Net

github.com/rosolko/WebDriverManager.Net



This small library aimed to automate the Selenium WebDriver binaries management inside a .Net project.

I started this project as a way if learning .Net and it has since grown into a fully fledged library. I have learned many skills through this and been I'm very proud of having this in my portfolio. If you don't have a project as awesome as this I would advise you make one.

## Experience

### tispr

tispr.com

Senior Backend Developer

September 2018 - Present

Participating in backend development. Using nodeJS and loopback.

Project about connecting, meeting and building communications, relationships andbusiness. Display your Work. Showcase your business. Get discovered. Connect to clients. Find the rightpros. Buy & sell services. Discover talented pros. Network with local businesses. Creating lasting workrelationships. It has native applications iOS, Android and Web, so you can easily work with applicationsanywhere.

### tispr

tispr.com

**Test Automation Lead** 

May 2017 - Present

Build and support automation process from scratch. Set-up and provide CI flow for testing and delivering. Create and bring some ideas to business. Work and integrate with all teams: business, developers and QA. Provide high level reports, plan and estimate work. Head test automation team and mentor it. Using java, selenide and selenoid.

Project about connecting, meeting and building communications, relationships andbusiness. Display your Work. Showcase your business. Get discovered. Connect to clients. Find the rightpros. Buy & sell services.

Discover talented pros. Network with local businesses. Creating lasting workrelationships. It has native applications iOS, Android and Web, so you can easily work with applicationsanywhere.

### **EPAM Systems**

epam.com

#### **Software Test Automation Engineer**

September 2016 - March 2017

Participating in manual automation testing. Fix and extend test automation framework. Analyze and document defects using bug tracking tools. Implement, fix and extend test scenarios and tests. Using java and appium.

Project about TV. It has native applications for iPhone, iPad or Android Devices (phones,tablets) and web applications, so you can watch your favorite shows and movies anywhere.

### **EPAM Systems**

epam.com

#### **Software Test Automation Engineer**

March 2016 - July 2016

Participating in automated tests framework development (discussing, testing and features purposing). Implementing automated tests for SAP SE products using developed framework: Automated tests for AEM Web UI (Selenium), Automated tests for analytics sent from AEM Web UI on custom actions (Fiddler + Selenium), Automated tests for AEM users and groups permissions (Sling API). Using c# and selenium.

Enterprise software to manage business operations and customer relations.

### **EPAM Systems**

epam.com

#### **Software Test Automation Engineer**

December 2014 - December 2015

Implementing test automation framework. Automated tests for Visual Data Discovery products: Web UI (Selenium), Desktop (Ranorex), COM (.Net), Console (.Net). Using c# and ranorex.

Software that helps companies make better decisions and solve business problems bysimplifying access to and analysis of semi-structured data information. It provides enterprise reportmanagement, online data analysis, Excel integration and more.

### **EPAM Systems**

epam.com

Software Testing Engineer / Software Test Automation Engineer

April 2013 - November 2014

Writing/updating/managing test cases/scenarios/checklists in the google documents. Developing test automation framework for:

CMS and Web UI. Using c# and selenium.

Platform with created ecommerce websites where you can buy branded promotional products. Also has 2 marketing sites. Impersonated and B2B shopping are supported.

## Education

### Yanka Kupala State University of Grodno

Information Systems And Technologies In Economics

2010 - 2015

Established in 1940, Yanka Kupala State University of Grodno a higher education institution, located in Grodno. It is the largest regional higher education institution in the Republic of Belarus, university complex integrating all levels of education.

During my time at University I learnt most of my key skills that have I have taken through my career such as teamwork and working to tight deadlines. I thouroughly enjoyed my time as university and learnt a lot about a healthy work life balance.

Degree (diploma): Technical school graduate

Faculty/College: Economics and management

### A Little More About Me

Alongside my interests in networks and software engineering some of my other interests and hobbies are:

- Cycling
- Gaming
- Play football
- Blogging
- Knitting (I hope someday)

Aliaksandr Rasolka - rosolko@gmail.com